Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Political Science, Honors Theses SC4-4493
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Political Science, honors theses
1962-2011
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Department of Political Science
SC4-4493
33.25 Linear Feet (352 volumes in 49 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Department of Political Science.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University Department of Political Science.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the University Archives from the Department of Political Science in several accessions. Additional theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Political science; Student papers.; Stanford University. Department of Political Science
- Theses, pre-1988
  - Abrams, Janet F., Democracy and the Single-Party System: Politics in Tanzania and Mexico., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Gordon M., The Prophets and the Politicians: Ideological Misperceptions of the American Left Wing., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Aleshire, David J., The English Poor Law, 1834-1876: A Study in Character Development., 1972 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Susan Katina, Economic Development in China: Rhetoric vs. Policy in Determining Outcome., 1983 (Box 1)
  - Bacon, John W., Soviet Priorities in Vietnam., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Barclay, Olivia, Cohesive Forces in Polish Communism., 1962 (Box 1)
  - Barnum, Randal, Political Influence in the City of Palo Alto: a Multiple Approach., May 1980 (Box 1)
  - Baskin, Scott, The Enhancement of Charisma and its Employment: A Prescriptive Theory for the American President., 1975 (Box 2)
  - Bass, Ronald J., The Role of Government in the Scandinavian Social Democracies., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Beim, David, The Communist System: A Study in Political Unification., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Belin, James M., Breakdown in Friendship: American-Chinese Relations, 1945-1950. (Box 2)
  - Bissell, Gail, Sisyphus and the Rock: Success Orientation and Goal Achievement in State Regulatory Agencies., 1976 (Box 2)
  - Bliss, Loa, The Political Machine and its Reform: A Structural-Functional Analysis., 1967 (Box 2)
  - Boeshe, Roger, Some Thoughts on Nietzsche's Notion of Truth., 1970 (Box 2)
  - Boles, Elizabeth Mary, The Role of Migration in Franco-Algerian Relations. [missing], 1981 (Box not specified)
  - Brase, David, Defending the First Domino: America Supports the French in Indochina. [missing], 1981 (Box not specified)
  - Brody, Richard I., A status quo model of international conflict., May 1977 (Box 3)
  - Brooks, John F., The Watts Revost: Summer 1965., 1966 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Edith G., The Berlin Wall: Microcosm of East-West Conflict., 1963 (Box 3)
  - Bufton, John Kelly, The Pople's Republic of China in the United Nations Economic and Social Council., June 1977 (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Thomas D., Changing Land Use Patterns in the Amazon River Basin of Brazil. [missing], 1981 (Box not specified)
  - Carp, Richard, Hippo., 1971 (Box 3)
  - Carpenter, William W., Soviet Arms Transfers to the Middle East, 1955-1980: Military Aid as an Instrument of Soviet Foreign Policy. [missing], 1982 (Box not specified)
  - Chamberlin, Carl W., In Re Gault: Implementation and Effect in San Francisco County., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Chandler, Douglas Eugene, The Political Process and the Indonesian Student Movement., 1970 (Box 3)
  - Cobey, Christopher E., Professional Campaign Managers in California Politics., 1971 (Box 4)
  - Cohan, Williams, A Psycho-Linguistic Approach to "Political Science"., 1969 (Box 4)
  - Connell, William D., Campaign Finance Reform: Political and Consitutional Implications of the 1974 Federal Election Campaign Act Amendments., 1976 (Box 4)
  - Copple, Brian W., Personal Obsession, Personal Failure: Franklin Roosevlt's Court Packing Debacle. [missing], 1982 (Box not specified)
  - Crandall, Virginia Lea, We Can All Be Leaders: An Analysis of Political Leadership: The U.S. Woman Sufferage Movement., June 1977 (Box 4)
  - Crocker, Stephen, The Future as the Past., 1963 (Box 4)
  - Dodge, F. Bruce, Comparative Enthusiasm at the International Level: A Research Design and an Application to Eastern Europe., 1964 (Box 4)
  - Eathman, Thomas T., The Management of Foreign Policy: Success and Failure in Kennedy's Collegial Approach., 1975 (Box 5)
  - Farbstein, Ken Tavrow, A Content Analysis of Solar Energy Magazines., 1979 (Box 5)
  - Feldstein, Thomas Mark, National Security Policy 1949-1950: the hydrogen bomb and NSC-68., 1979 (Box 5)
  - Ferguson, G. Bruce, The Relation of Political Authority to Economic Development in Ghana; 1946-1962. (Box 5)
  - Freivogel, Bill, The Political Aspects of the St. Louis-East St. Louis Interstate Air Pollution Problem. (Box 5)
  - French, James Kevin, Consumerism in the United States. (Box 6)
  - Furniss, Daniel J., On Equality of Educational Opportunity: The School Finance Cases., 1973 (Box 6)
  - Garrison, Ron, The Delano Grape Strike., 1967 (Box 6)
  - Gart, Thomas, Oil Shale Development: A Policy Analysis., 1980 (Box 6)
  - Gofen, Charlie, President Kennedy and the Neutralization of Laos, 1987; 1 folder(s)
  - Gonzalez-Aldape, Alicia, Women in British politics: A case study of Lady Randolph Churchill, Lady Astor, Margaret Thatcher, and Shirley Williams., 1974 (Box 6)
  - Gordon, Frederic Michael, In Pursuit of Pluralism: the role of environmental interest groups in public policy making. [missing], June 1981 (Box not specified)
  - Grady, Michael, The Constitutional Right of privacy., 1980 (Box 6)
  - Gwinn, Casey Gilbert, A Marriage of Convenience: The new right and the Christian Right. [missing], 1982 (Box not specified)
  - Hagen, Michael G., Preference Estimation: What People Think People Think. [missing], 1981 (Box not specified)
  - Hajda, Susan M., Theater Nuclear Forces: The Politics of Modernization and arms control. [missing], 1982 (Box not specified)
  - Halbo, Karen E., Affirmative Action and the Supreme Court. [missing], 1982 (Box not specified)
  - Hansen, John J., The Fundamentalist Personality., June 1981 (Box 6)
  - Haselton, Rick, The Consequential but Uncertain Burden: A History and Analysis of Interest Group Participation in Press Privilege Litigation., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Horn, John Stephen, The context of conservatism: a study of the political thought of John, John Quicy, and Henry Adams. [missing], December 1981 (Box not specified)
  - Isaacson, Irving M., School desegregation in the United States: The Role of President Dwight D. Eisenhower. [missing], 1982 (Box not specified)
  - Jarvis, Sonia Renee, The moral dimensions of Revolution. (Box 7)
  - Jennings, J. Richard, Native Subnationalism: theories and cases., 1976 (Box 7)
  - Joost, Peter, The Warm Springs Dam: A Case study and Analysis., 1980 (Box 7)
  - Juhnke, David, The search for strategic stability in the nuclear age: a bluewater alternative., June 1977 (Box 7)
  - Klein, Jill, To secure their unalienable rights: the Equal Rights Amendment., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Kotler, Ellen Maxine, Neutrality and peace: the China policy the United States rejected in the 1940s. [missing], 1981? (Box not specified)
  - Laing, James Stewart, Public financing of Congressional elections: a policy analysis., 1980 (Box 8)
  - Lampton, David M., Thoreau and the mass movement., 1968 (Box 8)
  - Larson, Barbara K., The Early years of the Egyptian Revolution, July 1952 to January 1955., 1962 (Box 8)
  - Lewis, David N., Teh Sino-Soviet dispute: the non-issue in Chinese politics., June 1976 (Box 8)
  - Lewis, Jacyn Otis Noel, The development of the social sciences in the soviet Union, 1970-1975: compromise and ideology., Spring 1976 (Box 8)
  - Littlehale, James Scott, The Carter Administration, Human Rights and El Salvador--the Breakdown of a Policy Alternative., 1988 (Box 8)
  - Livingston, Daniel M., Amending the United States constitution: An analysis of the Unanswered questions., 1979 (Box 9)
  - Long, Stephanie, Executive Order 9066: the tragic decision. [missing], 1982 (Box not specified)
  - Love, Julie, Stanford University: Win a few, lose a few. A success story. [missing], March 1981 (Box not specified)
  - Macris, Michael, The ultimate standard of political justification: a diachronic discourse., 1970 (Box 9)
  - Markunas, Paul J., The American conservative gospel according to William F. Buckley, Jr., 1978 (Box 9)
  - Mathewson, Vicki, Justice William O. Douglas: A survey and Analysis of His Critics., June 1981 (Box 9)
  - McHenry, Nancy L., Quest for Union: A study of the basis of the proposed federation of Malaysia including the Federation of Malaya, Singapore, Sarawak, Brunei, and North Borneo., 1963 (Box 9)
  - Michael, Douglas C., The politics and economics of welfare reform in the United States: a forecast for the 1980s., 1979 (Box 10)
  - Midler, Andrew R., The politics of Japan: trends and outlook. the resurgence of the Liberal Democratic party in Japan, 1982. [missing] (Box not specified)
  - Milch, Neal, Individual rights in the corporation., 1980 (Box 10)
  - Morris, John, The Judges., 1975 (Box 10)
  - O'Brien, Jr., Duncan M., School desegregation reexamined: a coneptual analysis of judicial policy implementation., Spring 1981 (Box 10)
  - O'Hara, Susan, Welfare reform, the Guaranteed income, and the Program for Better Jobs and Income., 1978 (Box 11)
  - O'Toole, Brian, The effec tof the political reform act of 1974 on the California political system., Sept. 1977 (Box 11)
  - Oseran, Deborah S., The vicious praitorian circle: the Bolibian Revolution of 1952 and the U. S. Aid., 1971 (Box 11)
  - Oxford, Alan Michael, Urbanization and multipartization: the decline of the Liberal Democratic Party in Japan., May 1978 (Box 11)
  - Pedder, William, Discrimination in Housing and employment: What Kind of Problem is it?., 1964 (Box 11)
  - Pickerell, Blair, The sale of military-related technology to the People's Republic of China., 1979 (Box 11)
  - Pierson, Gregory R., Change of Venue: An effective judicial process? the example of Stanislaus County., June 1981 (Box 12)
  - Poneman, David, National Health Insurance Needs and Problems., 1973 (Box 12)
  - Poston, Daniel, Rethingking Japan-U. S. relations in a new world: a critical analysis of current security agreements., 1976 (Box 12)
  - Poturica, Frank, Legal and Administrative problems in Controlling newsracks in Southern California., 1976 (Box 12)
  - Powell, Mark Albert, Change and personality as dynamic forces in history., August 1977 (Box 12)
  - Preston, Noralou, the significance of the 1961 Federal Election for the future of German politics., 1962 (Box 12)
  - Radcliffe, Peter, Democratic socialism in Jamaica: a discussion of its roots and legacies., 1982 (Box 13)
  - Rogers, John, In pursuit of survival: presidential leadership, advisory groups, and decision-making., 1976 (Box 13)
  - Roos, John V., Interest groups and American government: a case study of dairy cooperatives. [missing], Spring 1977 (Box not specified)
  - Ross, Terence, Views of the beginning and end: the death of meaning in the philosophy of history., 1980 (Box 13)
  - Ruhe, Jeff, Ulster: a bastard child., 1974 (Box 13)
  - Ruster, Jeff Edward, The economic and political environment of nuclear power and the exclusion of the public interest., 1981 (?) (Box 13)
  - Rutherford, Amanda, Trade unions and the common market., 1971 (Box 14)
  - Scarff, James E., The Politics of Wolf Control: An Inter-Disciplinary Evaluation of Public Policies, Political Institutions, and Political Science Analyses and Decision-Making Models., 1972 (Box 14)
  - Shaver, Dennis G., Bureaucrats and Political Officers: A Study of the Interplay Between the Two., 1971 (Box 15)
  - Sievers, Bruce, A Decision-Making Approach to the Study of the Communist System, A Research Design and Case Study., 1964 (Box 15)
  - Smith, Constance Bagley, An Analysis of the Soviet Decision to Begin Salt Negotiations., 1974 (Box 15)
  - Stanislaw, Jean Marie, An Empirical Test of a Typology of Unanimity., 1966 (Box 15)
  - Stedman, Stephen John, People, Organization, and Structure: Toward a Political Sociology of Revolution., 1979 (Box 15)
  - Steyer, James P., The Supreme Court, The Fourteenth Amendment, and American Capitalist Development: 1865-1905., 1978 (Box 15)
  - Stone, Margie K., Politics and policies of humanitarianism: a study of bilateral economic assistance to Latin America., July 1977 (Box 16)
  - Suniville, Gerald, The Effects of Secrecy and Security Classifications on American Democracy., 1976 (Box 16)
  - Thompson, Patricia, Alameda County's Release on One's Own Recognizance Program., 1978 (Box 16)
  - Trager, Elizabeth K., Racism, Sexism, and the Law: An Individual Perspective., 1981 (Box 16)
  - Upson, Mary-Michelle, Domestic Events and Foreign Actions: A Case of Ghana., 1964 (Box 17)
  - Upson, Michael H., Technocracy Inc., An American Social Movement., 1973 (Box 17)
  - Wierdsma, Theo B., Negative and Constructive Opposition to the Concept and Implementation of European Integration in the Netherlands., 1972 (Box 17)
  - Wirth, Peter, Measurement Effects on Voting in a Democracy., 1978 (Box 17)
  - Wolf, Bernard, The Relationship between the French Communist Party and the General Confederation of Labor., 1972 (Box 18)
  - Wood, Michael C., Civil Rights in Northern Ireland., 1974 (Box 18)
  - Woolf, Amy, Changing Perceptions and the End of SALT II., 1981 (Box 18)
  - Wu, Henry C. H., Equal Protection and Benign Discrimination: The Two-Edged Sword., 1978 (Box 18)
- Theses, 1988-1989; Accession ARCH-1989-286
  - Adler, Leonard, The Failure to Raise the Minimum Wage in the 1980s: Congressional Apathy or Successful Opposition?., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Anand, Rakesh, The Impact of Electoral Preferences on the Supreme Court Confirmation Process., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Chung, James, The United States and the Republic of Korea: A Reassessment of US-ROK Security Relations., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Colella, Ugo, The War Against the Story of the Triumphant Individual., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Dew, Joe, The Presentation of Socialism in California High Schools--A Study on the Transmission of Hegemonic Ideology., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Hayden, Drew, Bureaucratic Warfare: Military and civilian tensions in the Johnson Administration., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Jacobson, Karen A., Why does the U. S. support Israel? Comparative Analysis of Motivating Factors in U. S.-Israel Relations., 1989 (Box 2)
  - James, Terri, Single black mothers: issues and answers., 1989 (Box 2)
  - Nadan, P. Wales, Overextended Deterrence? Success and Failure in the 1990s., 1989 (Box 2)
  - Nowell, Kristin, America's strategic development of Micronesia: islands on reserve., 1989 (Box 2)
  - Robinson, Dean E., Race, Class, and the American dream: the political thought of W. E. B. DuBois, Martin Luther King, Jr., an dMalcolm X., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Steinberger, Mitchell J., Bork and Bad Timing: The Political Predictability of Robert H. Bork's Failed Nomination to the U.S. Supreme Court., 1989 (Box 2)
- Theses, 1982-1990; Accession ARCH-1991-062
  - Adams, Karen Ruth, Mineral Reliance and Economic Development: Copper in Zambia and Chile., 1986 (Box 1)
  - Bender, Dayna, The Gush Emunim: An Analysis of Alliance Building Between Religious and Secular Jews in Israel., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Bergstrom, Tod J., The Origin and Development of the Equal Protection of the Laws Doctrine., 1984 (Box 1)
  - Bevash, Suzanne Elena, Conservative Trend of the Supreme Court in Civil Liberties Cases 1976-1983 Terms., 1985 (Box 1)
  - Bunzel, Michael E., The Use of United States Arms Transfers to the Middle East as a Source of Specific Political Leverage: 1969-1986., 1987 (Box 2)
  - Burkhart, William, The Puzzling Question of Soviet Toleration of Change in Eastern Europe: The Cases of Romania and Czechoslavakia., 1985 (Box 2)
  - Carr, Edward A., Sexuality and the State: An Analysis of State Rationales for the Obscenity Regulation., 1984 (Box 2)
  - Celeste, Christopher Arthur, Restless Voyeurs., 1988 (Box 2)
  - Chiang, Kenneth, The People's Republic of China: Modernization by the Year 2000., 1984 (Box 2)
  - Cole, Luke Winthrop, Reagonomics: Power, Politics, Profits, and the American Political Economy., 1985 (Box 2)
  - Dort, Kenneth Kyle, World Leadership in the Postwar Era: The American Presidency and British Prime Ministry Since 1945., 1983 (Box 2)
  - Ford, Lewis, The Politics of Black Entrepreneurship., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Foyle, Douglas C., Poor Man's Armageddon: Chemical weapons proliferation., 1990 (Box 3)
  - French, Stephen R., Caring for souls within constraints of the state: the Church of England's quest for liturgical autonomy., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Fuentes, Rodolfo Rene, Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 (IRCA): Impact on California's Agricultural Labor Force., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Gawande, Atul A., The Political, biological, and philosophical failure of socio-biology and a humanist theory of human nature proposed., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Gelpi, Christopher, Defining Detente: The Importance of Policy Legitimacey in American Foreign Policy., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Gofen, Charlie, President Kennedy and the Neutralization of Laos., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Halperin, Philip, In Search of Rationales: The MX case study., 1985 (Box 3)
  - Hazard, Charles M., Poland: Political and Economic Reform: 1970-1989., 1990 (Box 4)
  - Hellman, Steven, Institutional Transfer and Revolutionary Communist Regimes., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Isaacson, Marcia R., Natural law as a justification for the protection of American civil liberties., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Kim, Angela S., Racial disparities in the criminal justice stystem: McClesky v. Kemp and its aftermath., 1990 (Box 4)
  - Larkin, Thomas F., The Constitution and the President: An instrument of policy or a fundamental charter for democracy?., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Marks, Edward David, The Impact of Black voting on the advancement of civil rights., 1984 (Box 4)
  - McAdam, Sam, Truman's decision to save lives: The atomic bomb and its options., 1987 (Box 4)
  - McFarlane, Robert A., The political development of the engineering profession, 1880-1932., 1990 (Box 5)
  - McKeever, Michael J., Reexamining the 1970s: a study of American strategic nuclear forces and policy., 1987 (Box 5)
  - McMahon, Jr., T. Vance, The power to make war: Congress, the President, and the War Powers Resolution of 1973., 1984 (Box 5)
  - Miller, Margo Sarah, Reconciliation: Revolution in Budget-making or one-time political triumph?., 1983 (Box 5)
  - Mitchel, Steve, The Israeli Connection: U. S. Foreign policy and the Arab-Israeli dispute, 1969-1979., 1983 (Box 5)
  - Myers, Andrew, Vision and mirage: an evaluation of the organization of American States., 1990 (Box 5)
  - Nadan, Christan, Nixon and Detente: Th Importance of policy legitimacy in American foreign policy., 1988 (Box 5)
  - Pizer, Bradley J., Public Interest group Law Reform: variables of Success., 1982 (Box 5)
  - Porter, Barry G., The Federal Death Penalty as a political issue., 1987 (Box 6)
  - Powers, Robin J., Collective responsibility for Minneapolis slumlords and their impact on housing, crime and human lives., 1990 (Box 6)
  - Purrington, Courtney, Toward the construction of a new crisis-prevention regime in Europe., 1983 (Box 6)
  - Reback, Sanford C., The evolution of American strategic nuclear doctrine: the search for flexibility., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Roosevelt III, Elliott, The Pentagon, technology, and complexity: problems, causes, and solutions. a critical analysis of sophisticated weaponry as it has been incorporated into the United States tactical air force., 1985 (Box 6)
  - Rossie, Christopher S., Independent Campaign Expenditure: free speech or demagoguery., 1982 (Box 6)
  - Rozansky, David Joel, The Road not yet taken: hard point defense as an American defense policy. a study of the doctrinal, military, and political issues necessary to determine desirability of Hard Point defense., 1986 (Box 6)
  - Sassaman, Steven, Varieties of Assimilationist visions: the education of immigrant children in teh United states and the Federal Republic., 1990 (Box 6)
  - Selman, Jeffrey C., Decision-Making in Practice: Israel's War in London., 1986 (Box 7)
  - Share, Eric D., Conflict and Cooperation: A Study of Party-Military Relations in the Soviet Union., 1985 (Box 7)
  - Siljak, Ana, Elites and Nationalism: The Case of the Serbian Communist Party., 1990 (Box 7)
  - Struthers, Steven K., An Interest-Group Perspective on the Administration Procedure Act: How Big Business Beat the New Deal., 1990 (Box 7)
  - Thomas, Andrew J., South Korean Capital Dependence on Japan: Economic Consequences and Political Implications., 1988 (Box 7)
  - Wildenthal, Bryan H., The Contradictory Politics of Judicial Decisionmaking., 1986 (Box 7)
  - Wong, Felicia J., Negotiating Salt: American Decisionmaking and the Prospects for a U.S.-Soviet Security Regime., 1988 (Box 7)
  - Young, Daniel J., Bowers vs. Hardwick: The Supreme Court of the United States Speaks about Homosexuality., 1988-89 (Box 7)
- Theses, 1987, 1991; Accession ARCH-1992-100
  - Booker, Brian R., W.E.B. Dubois and his View of the American Dream., June 1991 (Box 1)
  - Booker, Cory A., A Realistic View of Booker T. Washington., June 1991 (Box 1)
  - Dargan, Catherine Janine, A Comparative Study of the Economic and Political Progress of Blacks in South Africa and the United States During the 1970s and 1980s., May 1991 (Box 1)
  - Earnest, David C., Friend or Foe? The Problems of Assessment and Acceptance of Intelligence About Allies., March 1991 (Box 1)
  - Eldridge, Matthew J., Regimes Under Siege: A Comparative Analysis of Economic Sanctions Toward Rhodesia and South Africa., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Faucette, Jeffrey E., The Regulatory Tug-of-War: Interest Group Politics and Cable Communications., May 1991 (Box 1)
  - Gomez, Veronica, The Dominican Republic: Intervention and Democratic Development, 1965 and its legacy., May 1991 (Box 1)
  - Herrmann, John, Legislative Responses to the Perceived Ills of the 1960s: An evaluation of selected anti-poverty programs., May 1991 (Box 2)
  - Holland, Cindy, Roots of domestic ethnic relations in Botswana, Namibia, and Zimbabwe., June 1991 (Box 2)
  - Hollon, Gregory J., Havana in the Gorbachev era: the effects of changes in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe on Cuba 1985-1991., May 1991 (Box 2)
  - Holmes, Sarah Kristin, The 1989 Tiananmen Student movement: implications for democratic reform in China., June 1991 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Erik N., Access and Influence: Interest Groups, Policy, and the AMerican Association of Retired Persons., Juen 1991 (Box 2)
  - Levin, David A., Nuclear fallout: why the West fails to halt the spread of nuclear weapons to the Middle East., May 1991 (Box 2)
  - Levitsky, Steve, Domination and democratization in Revolutionary Nicaragua., May 1990 (Box 2)
  - Llop, Christina, The Mariel Wave., May 1991 (Box 3)
  - Lutsep, Marja Iive, The Family Reunion syndrome: the opinions, perceptions, and roles of exiles in Estonian politics., December 1991 (Box 3)
  - Moffeit, Kathleen L., The Abuse of the Peremptory Challenge Privilege., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Muchnick, Adam E., Emerging Economic policies of Chile's new democracy: a balanced approach to development., June 1991 (Box 3)
  - Paccione, Angela Veronica, The poltical consequences of the occuptaion of Trieste., June 1983 (Box 3)
  - Perrette, Clarisse, A revolution without bounds: the failure of law in Maoist China, 1949-1959., June 1991 (Box 3)
  - Rhow, Ekwan, Asian Americans in Higher Education: Quotas and the anathema of Affirmative Action., June 1991 (Box 4)